ARCHANA RAMESH

Irvine, CA - 92618 | 585-993-4145 | archanaramesh87@gmail.com archanaramesh.me| linkedin.com/in/archana-ramesh-aab02b127

UX Researcher / UX & Digital Strategist / UX Designer / Business Analyst

Professional Summary:

- Creative and detail-oriented emerging professional with experience conducting UX research, design, and strategy for web and mobile products.
- Skilled in sketching, storyboarding, wireframing, and prototyping multiple design iterations across platforms to incorporate feedback and continually refine UX.
- Perform in-depth analysis through usability studies, interviews, and testing to understand user pain points to deliver intuitive interfaces.
- Communicate with colleagues across functional areas to perform business analysis and document comprehensive business requirements.
- Results-focused with talent for uncovering usability and accessibility improvements that lead to increased user satisfaction and engagement.

Areas of Expertise:

- Contextual Inquiry
- Heuristic Evaluation
- User Research
- Affinity Diagrams
- Persona Creation
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Storyboarding
- Sketching
- Usability Testing
- Quantitative & Qualitative Analysis
- Market Research
- User Flows & Customer Journey Maps
- Email and website analytics
- JIRA
- Confluence
- Qualtrics

Core Technologies:

Design Tools: Sketch, InVision, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, Mockplus, Marvel, Adobe Experience Design,

Axure, Proto.io, Keynote, UX Pin, Litmus, Hotjar, Eloqua, Usertesting.com, Optimal Workshop

Web Development: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, XML

Education

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction, 2018

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science, 2016

R.V. College of Engineering, Bangalore, India

Experience Highlights

UX/UI Design Associate II | 2/2019 - Present

Ingram Micro, Irvine, CA

I lead the UX efforts for the Business Intelligence team and perform UX research & design for various products like email campaigns, portals, landing pages, and web applications for large tier-1 IT vendors. My role involves collaborating with a team spread across the globe and is geared towards being the point of entry in for projects, where I vet out steps like determining the research techniques to be used; and allocate the project to the right associate or lead the design effort on the project myself.

- Worked on campaigns (email and landing page offerings to resellers) based on persona segmentation and user research
 which entailed contextual inquiry / interviews, A/B testing, market research, competitive analysis, studying heat maps
 and other metrics. Used these findings to build a working prototype using UX pin. The idea was to strategically create
 more revenue by reinventing campaigns continuously.
- Worked on pricing portals, lead & opportunity generation portals, and reseller hubs by performing field research,
 designing usability studies, conducting surveys across products, analyzing results through qualitative & quantitative
 analysis, visualizing the data by creating user journey maps & data flow models, ideating, strategizing and prototyping a
 new product offering that aligns with the other Ingram Micro applications.
- Performed heuristic evaluations, usability testing, card sorting and suggested design changes on various data analytics dashboards which provided our team with valuable insights and improved the product offerings.

ARCHANA RAMESH

archanaramesh87@gmail.com | archanaramesh.me | linkedin.com/in/archana-ramesh-aab02b127

- Defined key performance metrics to measure the success of the UX projects (by studying the various types of heat maps like click, scroll and move maps; and different metrics like open rate, click through rate, etc. captured in Eloqua, Hotjar and Litmus; and leveraged these analytics and customer insights to help transform the product offerings.
- Designed the UX process and JIRA workflows for the team from scratch, consolidated and minimized SLAs, and increased productivity.
- Initiated the culture of having design hackathons in the team and encouraged the drive for innovation by starting new design channels. Led design efforts as a part of the 'Product Enhancements' committee and made critical design decisions for products across the Business Intelligence team.

UX Designer and Business Analyst (Internship) | 7/2018 - 12/2018

Saatchi & Saatchi, Torrance, CA

Performed UX research, UX design, usability testing, and business analysis for Toyota.com projects related to hybrid vehicles, Toyota Mirai, Toyota financial services and Toyota owner's websites. Created user stories and use cases; conducted market research for various projects.

- Led usability study for redesign of Toyota owner's homepage with newly created dashboards for showcasing, understanding, and grouping telematics data; explored optimal display for dashboard indicators and executed usability testing.
- Completed extensive research into user-centered design concepts, market research, and usability studies to recommend improvements to "Shopping Tools" and "Find a Dealer" features for increased sales.

HCI Graduate Student | 8/2016 - 12/2018

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

Enrolled in HCI master's program with coursework including Foundations of Human-Computer Interaction, Usability Testing, User-Centered Design Methods, Information and Interaction Design, Research Methods, and Foundations of Web Technologies 1 & 2. *Key projects include:*

- Corporate Website Redesign & Development: Completed UX design and front-end development for medical insurance company project (Pullano & Company), including user research, persona creation, wireframing, and website development.
- Non-profit Website Usability Study: Member of six-person team evaluating Bergen Swamp Preservation Society's website for usability issues in collaboration with website developer. Moderated multiple usability studies. Completed heuristic evaluations, recruited new participants using screeners and flyers, and executed usability testing to ensure website mapped to users' conceptual model and provide a good user experience.
- VR App Usability Study: Led and conducted usability study of one of the first-ever multi-user movie-screening virtual reality app, analyzed results, and recommended design modifications.
- Tourism Website Design and Development: Designed and developed tourism website for Bangalore, India using HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, JQuery, AJAX, and Bootstrap.
- **Coaster Crunch App:** Interviewed users, prepared affinity diagram, created personas, and developed wireframes and prototypes for digital fast pass app intended to reduce lines at amusement parks.
- **Voice Assistant Study:** Interviewed students and evaluated efficiency of voice assistants for academic purposes through quantitative analysis, qualitative analysis, experimental research on data compiled from student interviews.
- **Government Website Heuristic Evaluation:** Performed heuristic evaluation of the Virginia's EZ Pass website that uncovered 27 usability and accessibility issues.
- Accoutre App Design: Designed app to assist users in selecting clothing brands based on weather conditions and fashion trends. Conducted contextual inquiry; created flow models, sequence models, artifact models, physical models, and cultural models; prepared affinity diagrams; and developed low-fidelity and hi-fidelity prototypes and storyboards.
- Google Maps Evaluation (Desktop & Mobile Apps): Completed heuristic evaluation, conducted observations and interviews, performed contextual inquiry, created personas, and designed storyboards.

UX Designer (Internship) | 5/2017 - 8/2017

Pearit, Los Angeles, CA

Performed heuristic evaluation and led user research to design wireframes and prototypes for LA-based start-up's website, www.internmagic.com. Created new pages and redesigned home page, premium account page, cancellation page, and employer and student/employee account pages.